Muhammad Fathir Irhas

Software Engineer Jakarta Mobile/Whatsapp: +62-812-2444-1284 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/mfathirirhas

Email: fathir.irhas@outlook.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer in backend development. Having knowledge in Go Programming Language and tools related. Experienced in microservices architecture. Currently learning Rust and have interest in Rust-based web related project. Always learning to improve skills. Able to work individually or in team. Trying to achieve solutions with best possible way and practices.

EDUCATION

• Universitas Telkom

Bandung, Indonesia

Sarjana Komputer (Bachelor degree in Computer Science)

2012 - 2016

EXPERIENCE

• Lifepal(Remote)

Jakarta

Jakarta

 $Backend\ Engineer$

May 2022 - Oct 2022

- Working on telesales team on their telesales app in Rust.
- o Tech Stacks Rust, Tokio, Go, KubeMQ, Redis, Postgresql

• Shopee

Backend Engineer December 2021 - Maret 2022

• Tiket.com Jakarta

Backend Engineer

November 2020 - December 2021

- o **Team** Flight Prepurchase
- o Tech Stacks Go, Java Spring, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, RabbitMQ, etc.
- **Project** Creating internal mock server for mocking part of inter-services communications, especially partner and integration with flight supplier.
- Working on flight search caching tools to populate search cache preemptively.

• Tokopedia Jakarta

Software Engineer July 2018 - April 2020

- o Team Fintech
- Tech Stacks Golang, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, NSQ, gRPC, and GQL.
- Tokocash(discontinued) Create Whatsapp verification.
- Saldo Tokopedia Designed and refactor deposit transaction identification. Saldo Tokopedia separation into Saldo Penghasilan and Saldo Refund. Frontend revamp and frontend APIs. Saldo Internal dashboard. Refactor codebase architecture to comply to some SOLID principles, saldo separation and for code coverage. Cron services.
- Internal Dashboard Work on internal dashboard as backoffice to business and ops teams.
- **EGold** Create datadog monitoring dashboard for Tokopedia Emas buy and sell success, attempts rate and collect error reporting in the dashboard.
- Legacy Code Migrate some legacy code in Perl into Go.
- Monitoring Monitor services running through logs, grafana and datadog dashboard.
- Support Support other teams to integrate. Support ops teams relating issues from customers.

• Anabatic Serpong, Tangerang

Software Engineer/Technical Consultant

Nov 2016 - Jun 2018

- Tech Stacks Java(Spring), PHP(Codeigniter), MySQL, Javascript.
- Emporia Digital Raya Subsidiary of Anabatic. Worked on Eksporaja, a product as a channel partner with Alibaba for eksporter in Indonesia. Maintain Emporia main website. Worked on Udaily another product from emporia for apartment cluster management and daily stuffs.
- Anabatic Worked on client site. Supporting development in Allianz.

December 15, 2022

SKILLS

- Backend Development using Golang, Rust and few Java
- Databases with Postgresql, Mysql, SQLite, and Mongodb
- In-memory cache with Redis
- API with HTTP, gRPC, GraphQL, Message Queue.
- Some design patterns required in software developments.
- Maintaining and Debugging.
- Unit Testing and Integration Testing.
- Benchmarking and Monitoring.
- ...and others related.

LINKS

• **Github** https://github.com/mfathirirhas